The sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers is,

1^2 + 2^2 + ... + 10^2 = 385

The square of the sum of the first ten natural numbers is,

(1 + 2 + ... + 10)^2 = 55^2 = 3025

Hence the difference between the sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers and the square of the sum is 3025 − 385 = 2640.

Find the difference between the sum of the squares of the first one hundred natural numbers and the square of the sum.

Problem 6 「二乗和の差」 

最初の10個の自然数について, その二乗の和は,

1^2 + 2^2 + ... + 10^2 = 385

最初の10個の自然数について, その和の二乗は,

(1 + 2 + ... + 10)^2 = 3025

これらの数の差は 3025 - 385 = 2640 となる.

同様にして, 最初の100個の自然数について二乗の和と和の二乗の差を求めよ.
